# **Mohammad Alamin**

# Full-stack Developer

https://github.com/Alamin-eng in https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohammad-a-846376220/

A full-stack engineer graduate is available for an immediate start. Project experience gained in collaboration with professional developers and within teams. I am an effective collaborator, a problem solver, and a quick learner. Deeply committed to writing clean, efficient, and maintainable code. I am an enthusiastic programmer with experience working as a shift manager in other areas like retail, where I lead teams.

SKILLS			
Javascript     React     Node.js     PostgreSQL     HTML     CSS     Bootstrap			
Wordpress UI Design TDD Github Agile development Docker			
Adobe illustrator Tailwind CSS Linux Cloud computing AWS (currently learning)			
EXPERIENCE			
03/2024 – present  Travelodge Receptionist  • Duties include handling customer check-in/outs.  • Health and safety, and fire inspection, generating reports and organizing team members tasks.	London, United Kingdom		
O4/2023 – present  Code Your Future Full-stack Developer  Completed hackaton final project with a team of three developers and created the trainee milestone tracker's fully responsive website for the CYF.  Acquired expertise in using a GitHub project board to facilitate team collaboration within the Agile sprint framework for software development.	London, United Kingdom		

Present

libraries.

parts of the entire project.

 I have been creating projects, learning new tech and assisting students who lack technical knowledge of programming concepts.

Collaboration tools used - Slack, Google workspace.

Contributed 85% to the back-end and 20% to the front-end

Tech stack - React, Node.is, PostgreSQL, CSS and advanced

03/2022 - 11/2022

## Maroghi LTD

Office assistant

London, United Kingdom

- The role involved modifing websites using Wordpress and updating listings on other platforms.
- Gained experience working with Google Workspace and coworking tools like Trello.

2012 – 2021 **Seeking Asylum** 

From 2011 through 2022, I was seeking asylum in the UK.
 During this time I was volunteering and participating in career training. I was given refugee status in 2023, which allowed me to live permanently in the UK.

2007 - 2011 **KFC** 

London, United Kingdom

Team leader

- Lead a team of 6-8 people in a fast-paced business.
- · Completed all shift opening and closing-related tasks.

## **NOTABLE PROJECTS**

### Game play ☑

- Developed a fully responsive website created using advanced coding techniques optimised load times by 40%, and improved the overall user experience, leading to a 15% increase in user satisfaction.
- Lets users play more than 300 fantastic games for free. The website is quite comprehensive and easy to use.
- Tech stack React, Router, Javascript, CSS, Bootstrap.

SOFT SKILLS			
Punctuality	Organizational skill	Collaborative teamwork	
Time management	Commercial awareness	<ul> <li>Adaptability</li> </ul>	
	EDUCATION		
2021 – 2023	Full-stack Developer Code Your Future Full-stack engineer graduate trained in adv languages, Devops basics, Github collabor workspace collaboration, and Agile develo	ation, Google	
2020 - 2021	Frontend developer Free Code camp Trained in frontend development bootcam	London, United Kingdom p.	
2006 – 2008	Advanced Diploma in Information Technolo London Churchill college	<b>gy</b> London, United Kingdom	
	ORGANIZATIONS		

#### **ORGANIZATIONS**

## Herts Welcomes Refugees, Volunteer

# **Greenpeace, Volunteer**

#### **INTERESTS**

Learn new technology, digital art and animation, sustainable energy, and volunteer to make a positive impact on people's lives.

## **IMMIGRATION STATUS**

- Refugee status leading to permanent residency in the UK, unrestricted work allowed.
- No sponsorship is required.